Deis is a PaaS platform, which is built on both Docker and CoreOS.
In this demo, we will see how we can deploy an application on Deis.
For the demo, I have already configured a three node cluster using Vagrant.
Let us login to our Deis environment with the username I have created earlier.
We can deploy applications using Heroku buildpacks, Dockerfiles, and Docker images.
For the demo, we will use Heroku buildpacks and we’ll follow the instructions mentioned on the Deis website.
So, let us first clone the sample Ruby application on our workstation.
Now, as shown in the documentation, let us create an application,
which is named as “hungry-lakeside” and it has created a “Git remote” for our Deis environment.
Now, we can use a “git push” command to deploy our application on our Deis environment.
The “git push” command would send our code from the local workstation to the Deis, and then a build process would be triggered.
As we can see, the build process has detected our Ruby application,
which would then fetch the corresponding Ruby buildpack,
using which it would then build our application.
As we know, Deis uses Docker to deploy our application.
In the build process, Deis creates a Docker image with our application and then pushes it to an internal Docker Registry.
After pushing the resulting image to the registry, it would launch the application.
Our application is now launched and we can access it over the URL currently shown on the screen [http://hungry-lakeside.local3.deisapp.com].
We can scale our application with “deis scale” command.
We have now scaled our application to 3.
Now, if we access our application multiple times, we can see that it is being served by different containers.
So, in this demo we have seen how we can use Deis to deploy our application and then scale it up.